Jeremiah Fadugba

Data Scientist/ AI developer

jerryfadugba@gmail.com

+841634528447



Summary

A determined and ambitious person with the strength of active learning and the ability to adapt quickly to a new environment who has the strength to achieve a lot when self-motivated and inspired. I speak 2 programming languages and proficiently speak 1 human language. My main interest lies in Artificial Intelligence, Machine Learning, Natural Language Processing, Natural Language Understanding, Fuzzy (Logic, Clustering).

Top Skills

Python, MATLAB, Text Mining, Machine Learning, Research.

Soft Skills

Teamwork, Communication, Organization, Presentation, Listening, Leadership

Research Done.

 Big data clustering with the use of the random projection features reduction and collaborative Fuzzy C-Means

Research on big data is receiving the attention of many scientists. There are many solutions to common clustering problems, but big data clustering are beginning interested. In this paper, we proposed solution for big data clustering by reducing the features through a novel method in dimensionality reduction based on Johnson Lindenstrauss lemma and dividing the data into small sets then clustering locally and finally performing collaborative clustering (BDC-RPFR&CFCM). The experiment show that this solution give the better performance.

Dimensionality Reduction Based Fuzzy Ensemble Clustering For High-Dimensional Data

The ever increasing amount of data in this digital age, termed big data, calls for novel methods in unsupervised learning so as to combat the high dimensionality of most real world datasets and also provide a way of getting good clustering solution. This work provides a novel approach to dimensionality reduction using a revised approach of random projection and thereafter deviating from the commonly used clustering algorithm, we provide a useful way of ensemble learning on clustering algorithms.

Application of Game Theory in Advertisement

As every company or organization is profit oriented, with similar companies as a competitor. Application of Game theory in Advertisement highlights ways you can use a mathematical concept called Game Theory, to stay ahead of the game in advertisement using Tisos Chemical Industry as a case study.

Experience

AI Developer

Nal Vietnam Jsc, Duy Tan, Hanoi, Vietnam

August 2017 - Present

Deep Learning based Object detection. (Product)

Facial Recognition using deep learning. (Product)

Using Generative Adversarial Networks for generating images with few data. (Research)

Horizontal (Industry specific) ChatBot based on deep learning. (Research)

IOS application for detecting menu (Product).

Optical character Recognition. (Japanese characters). (Research and Product).

Graduate Research Intern (Remote) Hanoi, Vietnam

FPT Technology Research Institute, Duy Tan,

April 2017 – August 2017

Research related to Text mining.

Working on Text Auto Summarization

Building a Chabot. And many more

IT Instructor

SEAM Center, Keangnam Building, Hanoi, Vietnam

August 2016 - Present

Teaching teenagers and young kids in learning how to:

**Code in C language

**Making 3D designs

**Use Scratch to build apps, games and learning how to code.

Data Scientist (Intern)

Metrixa - Data Driven Digital Marketing, Hanoi. Vietnam

April 2017 - June 2017 (3 months)

Projects:

Cohort Analysis: Understanding users that shares the same peculiar characteristics.

Basket Analysis: Knowledge discovery on how the shopping behavior of customers.

Data:

Dataset relating to online advertisement and digital marketing.

Android Developer

SEA-Solutions Software Company, Hanoi, Vietnam.

December 2015 - August 2016 (8 months)

Developing Tried, Tested and Trusted Software Applications on Android platform.

Technical assistance

Adipat Consult, Ibadan, Nigeria

June 2013 - December 2013 (6 months)

Preferring solutions to software issues.

Supporting technical and engineering personnel with project support duties.

Compiling technical reports.

Ensuring that all technical operations of the company run smoothly.

Assistance to the chief consultant engineer.

Production Assistant

TISOS Chemicals, Ibadan, Nigeria.

August 2009 - December 2010 (1 year 4 months)

Maintaining and servicing all production equipment's,

Aiming at delivering products to customers at the right time and keeping records of daily productions.

Education

FPT University

Hanoi, Vietnam

Master's Degree, Data Science, 2015 – 2017

University of Ibadan

Ibadan, Nigeria.

Bachelor's Degree, Mathematics, 2011 - 2015

Activities and Societies: Independent Mathematics Student Electoral Committee (IMSEC)

Projects Done

Determine the theft and burglary crime rate per district in Philadelphia over the past 10 years.

Implementing data mart, for the ultimate purpose of visualization using raw data that has undergone rigorous data cleaning to:

Determine whether Philadelphia has gotten safer in the last decade

Conclude on how secure Philadelphia is for siting a business warehouse.

Discern the likelihood of losses incurable as a result of burglary and theft.

Estimate likely premium billable for relevant insurance policies.

Sequence Tagging With Hidden Markov Model

Sequence tagging is a fundamental problem in natural language processing, which

is a core component of any text mining system.

There are numerous machine learning models for solving sequence tagging

problem, including Hidden Markov Models (HMM), Maximum Entropy Markov

Models (MEMM), or Conditional Random Fields (CRF).

In this project, we implemented a second-order HMM to tag a given English sentence with its parts- of-speech which is trained and tested on the Brown corpus.

Biological Sequence Analysis

A project to determine if a biological sequence is a gene or not.

Given a splice-junction-gene sequence, we implemented the Hidden Markov Model (precisely the Forward Algorithm) to determine whether a 60 character sequence (A, C, G, T) is a gene or not.

Text Summarization

This project takes was developed to summarize all news article in a particular news website. It only supports English Language.